I am a computer scientist specialized in the area of program analysis and verification, distributed systems, and cyber-physical systems. Program verification is the part of software engineering dedicated to showing that a piece of software has no bugs. In my academic research, I worked on improving software by developing theoretical models to better understand software artifacts and algorithms to analyze them.

algorithms to analyze them.	
	Professional Experience
2022.10	Quality assurance lead , <i>Signaloid</i> , Cambridge, UK Remote work from Switzerland
2022.01–2022.09	Consultant, Signaloid, Cambridge, UK Remote work from Switzerland
2016.12–2021.11	Research group leader , <i>Max Planck Institute for Software Systems</i> , Kaiserslautern, Germany
2013.10–2016.9	Postdoctoral researcher, MIT CSAIL, Cambridge, USA In Martin C. Rinard's group.
	Education
09.2009–09.2013	PhD , <i>Institute of Science and Technology Austria</i> , Klosterneuburg, Austria Under supervision of Thomas A. Henzinger
09.2007–07.2009	Master , École Polytechnique Fédérale, Lausanne, Switzerland Master in Computer Science with specialisation in Foundations of Software
09.2004–07.2007	Bachelor , École Polytechnique Fédérale, Lausanne, Switzerland Bachelor in Computer Science
08.1999–06.2004	Maturité gymnasiale, Lycée Collège des Creusets, Sion, Switzerland High School in math section (specialisation: physics and numerical methods)
	Interships
07.2012-08.2012	Intern , <i>Max Planck Institute for Software Systems</i> , Saarbrücken, Germany One month internship under supervision of Ruzica Piskac.
05.2012–06.2012	Research consultant , <i>Microsoft Research</i> , Redmond, USA Three weeks consulting mandate to work with Shaz Qadeer and Ethan Jackson.
11.2011-03.2012	Research intern , <i>Microsoft Research</i> , Redmond, USA Three months internship with Shaz Qadeer.
07.2007–09.2007	Intern, Simon Fraser University, Vancouver, Canada Two months internship at the Software Reliability Lab with Dirk Beyer.
2006–2008	Research assistant , <i>École Polytechnique Fédérale</i> , Lausanne, Switzerland Part-time research assistant at Model and Theory of Computation laboratory.

Skills

- Leadership
 - Managing a research group with 3 PhD students
 - Organizing conference and workshops with up to 50 participants
- Programming
 - Github profile: https://github.com/dzufferey
 - Programming language:
 - \cdot experienced in C/C++ and Scala
 - · competent in Java, Python, Typescript, and shell scripting
- Languages
 - French (native)
 - English (proficient)
 - German (upper-intermediate)

Academic and Teaching Experience

Here are a summary of my academic career in numbers. (Details in my long for academic CV.)

- I published 37 peer-reviewed scientific papers.
- My results have been cited more than 1200 times and my h-index is 18.
- I organized 3 international conference and workshops.
- O I have been in 20 program committee and reviewed for 26 conferences and journals.
- I have supervised 3 PhD students and 3 master thesis.
- O I co-taught 7 classes in computer science at the master level (TU Kaiserslautern).

References

Available upon request

Awards

- Excellency Scholarships at the Master level from EPFL.
- Graduated best in class from my Bachelor at EPFL.
- Silver Medal of the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (Regionals, South-Western Europe) in 2007 with EPFL (6th place, Swiss champions, team with Frédéric Dubut and Christian Kauth)
- Bronze Medal of the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest (Regionals, South-Western Europe) in 2006 with EPFL (9th place, Swiss champions, team with Frédéric Dubut and Abhishek Garg)